Finding Aid for Arthur Brown family papers, ca. 1873-1945
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Arthur Brown family papers ca. 1873-1945
Brown family.
1 linear foot
8562 Aa 2
Ann Arbor, Michigan, family. Correspondence, other papers and photographs of Arthur Brown, Ann Arbor attorney and mayor, and officer and director of the Washtenaw Abstract Company; also papers of his wife, Cora Pulcipher Brown, largely concerning work with Americanism Committee of the Daughters of the American Revolution during World War II.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of the estate of Mrs. Helen Brown Haller (donor no. 6321 ) and came to the library in 1979.
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Arthur Brown was born in Saline, Michigan on February 14, 1864. Orphaned, he nevertheless received a solid education, first attending Albion College and later the Law School of the University of Michigan, from which he graduated in 1894.
While Brown was attending law school, he served as county clerk of Washtenaw County. Brown remained active in politics, as a Democrat, throughout his life. He served in Ann Arbor as an alderman, member of the Board of Education, and mayor (1903-1905). He was defeated twice in an effort to become circuit judge.
Privately, Brown maintained an active and respected law practice. He also served on the board of directors of two local banks and was both an officer and director of the Washtenaw Abstract Company.
Arthur Brown died September 21, 1932. He was survived by his widow, Cora Pulcipher Brown, who was a founder and active member of the Sara Caswell Angell chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution.
The Brown family collection is unfortunately a fragment of materials with very few of the papers created by either Arthur or Cora Brown surviving. What remains relate almost exclusively to the legal career of Arthur Brown, in particular to his service to various persons as a collector of bad debts, and to Cora Brown's work with the Americanism Committee of the Daughters of the American Revolution during World War II.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--History.; Washtenaw Abstract Company (Ann Arbor, Mich.).; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Daughters of the American Revolution.; Lawyers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Brown, Arthur, 1864-1932.; Brown family.; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Haller family.; Haller Jewelry (Store: Ann Arbor, Mich.); Interiors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.
Contributors:
Brown, Arthur, 1864-1932.; Brown, Cora Pulcipher.
Genre Terms:
Ambrotypes.; Photographs.
- Family papers
  - Genealogical material
    - Brown family (Box 1)
    - Doty-Pulcipher families (Box 1)
    - Haller (George) family (Box 1)
  - Arthur Brown biographical material (Box 1)
  - Cora Brown activity in Americanism Committee (Box 1)
  - Sarah Caswell Angell chapter, D.A.R. (World War II) (Box 1)
  - Brown home (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1897-1901 (Box 1)
    - 1902-1903 (Box 1)
    - 1904-1905 (Box 1)
    - 1906-1907 (Box 1)
    - 1908-1910 (Box 1)
  - Summaries of cases, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Financial records (legal fees?), 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - Institute of Metaphysics class notes, 1873, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1896 (Box 1)
    Photographs in collection include unidentified ambrotypes, presumably of family members; photos of the Pulcipher family home, of William Jennings Bryan's visit to Ann Arbor in 1896 and of the interior of the Haller Jewelry store; and a portrait of Arthur Brown.